# NIKITA KOSTIN

Espoo, Finland · nskostin96@gmail.com · +358414960156 · https://nik31096.github.io

#### Profile

Highly initiative and self-motivated machine learning engineer with 6+ years of academic and industry experience. Proficient in Python and has solid knowledge of machine learning algorithms. Proven record of contributions to software development projects from top tech companies. Demonstrated teamwork and supervision skills in several academic and industrial projects.

#### SKILLS

Programming: Python, C++, Julia, MATLAB, PyTorch, TensorFlow, ROS2, Git, Docker, LaTex

Languages: English (C1), Swedish (B1), German (A2), Finnish (A1), Russian (native)

#### Work experience

Aalto UniversityEspoo, FinlandResearch ScientistNov 2021 - Present

- Research in safe and robust reinforcement learning algorithms for robotics.
- Developed uncertainty-aware safe exploration for reinforcement learning using text-based constraints using a Bayesian cost model, making the agent safely operate in complex, unknown environments (under review).
- Developed robust reinforcement learning algorithm for fast adaptation to unseen dynamical changes using adaptive control (under review).

#### Huawei Research Center

Moscow, Russia Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

Machine Learning Engineer

- Research and development of deep learning algorithms for image enhancement and super-resolution.
- Developed a deep learning solution for demosaicing of underscreen camera photos that improved the quality of the images.
- Developed a super-resolution algorithm based on Normalizing Flows that improved the quality of the underscreen camera photos.

### Samsung R&D Institute

Moscow, Russia

Machine Learning Engineer

Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

- Research and development of automation algorithms for cloud and mobile applications.
- Developed OpenStack system installation automation that speed up the deployment of the system on a new location.
- Developed AI-based Mobile Testing Automation for Android using Reinforcement Learning that accelerated new features testing.

## EDUCATION

Aalto University PhD in Electrical Engineering (not completed), GPA: 4.52	Espoo, Finland Jan 2022 - May 2024
Lomonosov Moscow State University M.Sc in Applied Mathematics, GPA: 4.05	Moscow, Russia Sep 2018 - May 2020
Lomonosov Moscow State University B.Sc in Physics, <i>GPA: 4.51</i>	Moscow, Russia Sep 2014 - May 2018
Conferences and Workshops	
Teaching assistant at ProbAI  Lead TA on Normalizing Flows section of Nordic Probabilistic AI summer school.	Helsinki, Finland Jun 2022
Teaching assistant on RL course TA on the Reinforcement Learning course.	Helsinki, Finland Sep 2022 - Present
International Workshop of Intelligent Autonomous Learning Systems Organized by the Intelligent Autonomous Systems lab from TU Darmstadt.	Kleinwalsertal, Austria Aug 2023
Generative Modeling Summit Organized by Yandex, it presented the latest technologies behind YaGPT.	Belgrade, Serbia Sep 2023
ELLIS Robust Machine Learning Workshop Workshop covered important topics of robustness of ML, LLMs and Human-Compute	Helsinki, Finland er Interaction. Jun 2024